RG 004:110, Plainville Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Plainville Probate Court records
1910-1978
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Plainville District)
23.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1910-1975; Real estate certificates, 1935-1978; Probate files, None.
RG004_110
2012-016, 2014-013
Historical Note
Plainville, Hartford County, Town established in July 1869, Parent Town: Farmington
The Plainville Probate District was constituted May 1909, from the Farmington Probate District. The Plainville Probate District merged with the Bristol and Plymouth Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #19 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bristol, Plainville, and Plymouth.
Town of Plainville, Probate District chronology:
May 1869 - May 1909, Farmington District
May 1909 - January 4, 2011, Plainville District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #19 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Record books, volumes 1-47, 1910-1975. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 47. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Real estate certificates, 1935-1978.
Probate files, None.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 47.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Plainville
Places:
Plainville (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2012-016, record books, 1910-1975 and accession 2014-013, real estate certificates, 1935-1978 are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1, applications, returns, 1910-1928; volume 2, admin. accts., inventories, returns, 1910-1916; and volume 5, wills, 1895-1917, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2012-016 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 18, 2012, August 13, 2013, and September 5, 2013.
The real estate certificates in accession 2014-013 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on September 5, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1910-1975; 22.5 cubic feet (47 volumes); 2012-016
  - Orders and decrees, 1910-1919 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1910-1931 (Volume 2)
  - Applications and returns, 1910-1928 (Volume 3)
  - Administration accounts, inventories and returns, 1910-1916 (Volume 4)
  - Wills, guardians, petitions, orders, miscellaneous, 1910-1917 (Volume 5)
  - Administration accounts, inventories and returns, 1916-1920 (Volume 6)
  - Wills, guardians, petitions, orders, miscellaneous, 1917-1927 (Volume 7)
  - Orders and decrees, 1917-1927 (Volume 8)
  - Administration accounts, inventories and returns, 1920-1932 (Volume 9)
  - Applications and returns, 1928-1941 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1924-1930 (Volume 11)
  - Wills, guardians, petitions, orders, miscellaneous, 1921-1937 (Volume 12)
  - Orders and decrees, 1930-1934 (Volume 13)
  - Bonds, 1931-1942 (Volume 14)
  - Administration accounts, inventories and returns, 1931-1943 (Volume 15)
  - Return of claims and administration accounts, 1933-1945 (Volume 16)
  - Reports of trustees, conservators, guardians and estates, 1930-1948 (Volume 17)
  - Orders and decrees (Volume 18)
    This volume is blank.
  - Wills (Volume 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1945 (Volume 20)
  - Applications and returns, 1941-1954 (Volume 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945-1951 (Volume 22)
  - Bonds, 1942-1947 (Volume 23)
  - Inventories, 1943-1955 (Volume 24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Volume 25)
  - Return of claims and administration account, 1945-1953 (Volume 26)
  - Reports of trustees, conservators, guardians, and estates, 1949-1959 (Volume 27)
  - Wills (Volume 28)
  - Applications and returns, 1954-1964 (Volume 29)
  - Return of claims and administration account, 1954-1959 (Volume 30)
  - Inventories, 1955-1966 (Volume 31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1960 (Volume 32)
  - Bonds, 1957-1970 (Volume 33)
  - Reports of trustees, conservators, guardians and estates, 1960-1967 (Volume 34)
  - Return of claims and administration account, 1959-1964 (Volume 35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1964 (Volume 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964-1967 (Volume 37)
  - Applications and returns, 1965-1975 (Volume 38)
  - Return of claims and administration account, 1964-1969 (Volume 39)
  - Wills (Volume 40)
  - Inventories, 1966-1974 (Volume 41)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1970 (Volume 42)
  - Reports of trustees, conservators, guardians and estates, 1967-1974 (Volume 43)
  - Bonds, 1970-1974 (Volume 44)
  - Return of claims and administration account, 1970-1974 (Volume 45)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1975 (Volume 46)
  - Wills (Volume 47)
- Real estate certificates, 1935-1978; 1 cubic foot; 2014-013
  - Real estate certificates, 1935-1978 (Box 1)